Good morning. So again, I always talk about this internet as a place that has the power to
be a good and bad. One of the individual ways that I've experienced the dehumanizing of this,
the dehumanization by this internet is when people who have my phone number
will choose to make content about me from a place of ignorance versus speaking to me.
Hey, Jackie, Charles, that rocking chair. And, um, you know, we, we have choices that we can make
you guys in terms of how we are interacting with each other. And this morning I was talking about
on my Patreon about how there's a language barrier that many of us have that may not be just how,
like what language we're speaking in terms of, you know, whether it's a Latin language,
a Germanic language, Slavic, et cetera, et cetera. Right. So whether we're speaking,
you know, Chinese, Mandarin, uh, or English or Gullah Geechee, et cetera. Uh, sometimes our language
barrier is whether we speak in lack or abundance. Hello, I am Lartzi in Moscow. Privyets! Kogdila!
Uh, watch, we have queen bee and greens, boss of untree! I love it. And so that, that difference
in lack and abundance can cause so many, uh, communication barriers because even if, good
morning, Vancouver, Canada, even if you are attempting to support somebody, if you're coming
from a lack language, it will come off different to someone who, um, comes from an abundance place.
It may come off as disrespectful. It may come off as invasive. It may come off as, um, not supportive
at all. And that's something that I think we have to really put ourselves and our energy to change
changing. So when I say the difference between lack and abundance is that so many of us, when
we are looking at, um, errors or, or ways, points of improvement in others, we will verbalize
it by identifying what's missing versus identifying the thing that requires more abundance and leading
with that. So the example I used on my Patreon was, okay, so I just get overwhelmed with putting
away my clothes. So I will wash my clothes and they will end up just like existing in the
hampers. I have so many hampers because I hate putting away clothes. So I will continue to wash
the clothes, but the clothes getting actually put away. That's a whole other beast. Then,
so then there's like a part two of this, which is the clothes going from the hampers to being
sorted. That part two can get stuck. Part two can get stuck because the clothes are clean.
The clothes are clean. The clothes are clean. The clothes are now sorted. However, they now
have to go into their respective places. That's three whole different steps, y'all. And sometimes
that third step, it'll make it, it'll make it. Okay. So someone who doesn't have that issue
per se might look at that and be like, oh my God, you're messy. Right? Sometimes they might
look at that and be like, oh my God, you're disorganized. Or, oh my God, like you're, I don't
know. They just might find a way to make that into a negative. And when really the thing that's
stopping you from putting the clothes away, it got nothing to do with you being messy.
It may have something to do with exactly right here. I love you guys. It may have something to do
with vibes. It may have something to do with it being a non monotonous. It may have something to
do with you being overwhelmed with just the task at the task itself. Right? Because there might be like
so many, it might've been built up so much that there's just so much. It might be also just, you
don't have the time. Right? And if you're coming from a lack language, not necessarily a lack,
a lack mindset, but a lack language, you might say, man, you can't leave all them clothes like that.
For someone like me, that is going to be offensive. If someone, if you tell some, if you tell someone
like me, man, you can't leave them clothes like that, I'm going to get defensive. Because actually
I can't, like I've been living with them like this for quite some time. Don't tell me what to do.
And you also know that you want to put the fucking clothes away. You do. You just impeded.
So the abundance mind state. Okay. The abundance mind state says,
instead of asking, instead of telling you like, Oh, you can't, you can't leave your clothes like
that, or you shouldn't leave your clothes like that. The abundance language will be,
how can we make more room for you on your bed? I feel like the clothes are taking up room that you
should get to and have it. Now you have to want to change that language. You have to want to change
that language, not just for yourself, but for the other person. And also that is literally improving
to your community. When we choose to, to see each other that way, we change how we also change,
how we also view our lives. Sometimes it's hard to change how we're viewing ourselves. So sometimes,
you know, it may be that your start in changing how you view your own situation is how you view others.
Right? So sometimes it's like, okay, you might be looking at your situation like, damn, like my shit
is whack. I'm stuck. Like I'm in lack, et cetera, et cetera. Um, and you just can't get out of that.
So it might be easier to look at someone else's situation and LOL, I asked Charlie said,
I just pushed a shirt with my foot. It might be easier to then start by looking at someone else's
situation and challenging yourselves to see that situation through a lens of abundance. And let me
tell you, that is not easy. Okay. We live in a world that focuses on lack. We live in those of us who
live in a capitalist society. We literally live in a world that is grounded in scarcity.
It is completely, it thrives. It doesn't thrive actually, but it, it functions on creating a false
sense of scarcity. So unwittingly you are, um, conditioned to view everything through less.
You are indoctrinated to see everything through a lens of less. That's what you, that's what has
you thinking that Democrats are somehow valuable, even though they are literally telling you they're
just the lesser of two evils. So it's literally teaching you that, that less is enough. It's not
engineering you to actually live off abundance, which is very present and capable and, and available to
all of us. Now, someone here said too early in the morning for this, and they rolled their eyes and
they're Grenadian. And what I would say to that is that I would encourage you to lean more into the fact
that when we are awake in the morning, our minds are at their highest capability because they are fresh.
They are fresh. They are open. They are meeting the day. Right. And, um, doing so is to me the,
like meeting the day with messaging of, you know, challenging our minds to think differently to me
is, is the best time to do it. Cause now I don't have the, the nonsense of the whole day
on top of the new lesson where you're trying to like make room. Nope. Amina Bay, bless you. Empress.
Hi, Whitney. Nah, carob. I don't know. I don't know what nonsense you're speaking of, but, um,
as a Grenadian, I will absolutely say that ignorance has no place in my space. And when I wake up in the
morning, my brain is sharp because what often happens is I go to bed with an issue or problem or
a challenge. And that space between sleep and awake, the answers come, the answers arrive.
You know, I was trying to sort through this conflict that I was having, where I was trying to figure out
a communication breakdown that me and my man keep having. And it's a communication breakdown that
was confused. It's com, it was confusing to me. Is it, that's what it's called Marquis? Say that.
It was confusing to me because it's two people that are genuine, that are kind,
and that keep having a particular community, communication breakdown around genuine and
kindness. And so it was like, what, what is this? What is this? So I went to bed challenging
myself to figure out like, what is this? And something I talked about also in my morning musings
on Patreon is as a, as a person with pattern recognition and empathy, I oftentimes, you know,
end up seeing this before someone else. So then that can make someone else think that you're like
focusing on dysfunction, et cetera, et cetera. And it's like, no, it's not that it's just that I can
see the thing. I can see it. I can see that there's a thing. I need to figure out what that thing is.
Because that thing is in the way. That thing is in the way. And I solved it.
And so the other thing that ends up happening is then you are tasked with sharing with somebody,
like, this is the thing that I've discovered. And really it just ends up being like, are they
accepting of it? Are they not? You know, are they interested in, you know, tweaking it with their,
of course, self-knowledge of themselves? Are they interested in engaging? You know, that really
ends up being the task. But for, for those of us who are empaths and who have pattern recognition,
oftentimes we are able to see the trigger. We are able to see what the breakdown is before the actual
person who is triggered. Absolutely. You're able to see you, you, you be getting triggered. Even that
they, they may, they may not even notice that that's what's happening. You're like, you be getting
triggered. You be getting triggered. Then the next step for the pattern recognitioner is what is the
thing that's triggering you? What, what, what, what is happening every time you get triggered?
Now here's the doozy. They might be triggering you. So that's what's been happening with me and my man.
His trigger is triggering me. So now it's TriggerFest 2000. It's TriggerFest 2000.
And once you hit it, once you enter TriggerFest 2000, y'all, it, it, it don't work. It don't make it.
It don't make it. So I tasked myself with, okay, Amanda, what is he triggering you?
How is he triggering you? And then I engaged in conversation to try to understand
why they were upset, right? I took myself out of it. I took why I was upset out of it. I took it out.
I took it out y'all. I took it out. I said, let me, let me understand what upsets you.
And the thing is, is that we are not raised in a world where we have emotional intelligence or
language to communicate our emotions. So, you know, being able to engage in that communication
can sometimes really be difficult because you don't want to trigger the person again. You also
don't want someone to feel interrogated. You don't want them to feel probed. So it does take a certain
level of kind of like lightheartedness and softness to try to keep the conversation going to get the
data, to get the data. And you have to be willing to do this. And that's the thing that a lot of us
are not willing to do, but this takes, this takes time and it takes energy. And it's taken me a lot
of practice over life. Someone this morning said that I like humility and I find that hilarious because
the amount of humility it takes to be able to say, I'm going to remove my triggeredness to try
to understand this. And, you know, let's be real. Like people will show you in, in their explanation
of why they are upset. They're going to show you whether the reason that they're upset is one that
is like genuine and from a pure place or one that is some asshole shit. And then you can perceive
however you, you know, however you see fit. But if in that conversation you realize that like that
person was genuinely trying to show care or that person was just being curious, you can, you can now
then say, okay, so the core is there. What is the blockage in the drain? Right? Cause it's all energy.
So what is the blockage in the throat chakra? Cause you're, you're starting from a good place
and then it's getting blocked and coming out in some other way that is not it. Right? Because for me,
my trigger is, um, being told what to do in a way that is, um, negative, right? Being told what to do
in a way that's being negative. And yes, we are absolutely trained as women to do pattern recognition
and to understand emotional intelligence. And where I'm going in this conversation is how do you empower
someone to do that themselves? I'm not going to block you, Pam girl, because I understood what
you said. Right? So don't sweat it. Um, that really is the thing though. It's, it is how do you empower
and listen, someone asked, how do you tell the difference on who to keep? For me, the difference
is, do they want that empowerment and do they enact it? Hi, Kuwait. Hi, Ms. Azima, Ms. Aziza. Sorry.
That's my leg. Um, I am not interested in being with anyone, working with anyone or being friends
with anyone who does not want to empower themselves with emotional intelligence, period. Who does not
want to empower themselves with brutal softness, which is the name of my next album, brutal softness.
What I mean by that is softness that can cut through the, the shame, the negativity, the hardness,
brutal softness, a truthness, a truth, a truthness, a truthiness that cuts it away. You know, that,
that, that, that dissolves water. Look at what water does to rock. Look at how water
in all of its smoothness in all of its softness can wear away at rock at hardness. And I'm not calling
it tact because tact is simply just knowing when to say something. Um, Oh, now you're over here telling
me what to do and I don't, so you can go and think about how you're talking to me. Um, cause tact is
simply knowing what to say and when to say it. And, um, to be honest, I think that just is not enough
of an explanation of what is required because you, you have to have also compassion. You also have to
have self-awareness, you, you know, like just simply saying the word tact doesn't send all that
messaging to somebody and your version of tact may not be someone else's version. And that's really what
we're talking about here. Right. So, you know, it, it, it requires much more explanation than just
simply one word. So I say all this to say that I then as the pattern recognizer, recognizer have to
communicate to someone, this is what I'm recognizing. And yes, there is tact involved in that. Um, however,
softness is not simply just a matter of saying something at the right time in the right way.
It's a way of life. It's a way of life. It's how you communicate in language. It's how you
communicate in action. It's how you choose to care. Right. And, um, it's how it's literally your entire
existence. And that softness comes for you too. It's that water, right? Some folks,
they are not able to be moved. So you move around them. Someone had a question. What if you are tired
of caring, especially with white people move around them, move around them. That's what I say.
What is the role of the United States in its inability to force Netanyahu to stop the war?
It's not an inability. The United States is completely capable. The United States, however,
is ruled by the same hand that rules Netanyahu. They are partners in crime. So why would they stop
the war? The war is essential in order for them to retain power. They literally just voted and passed
the Israel-United States integration bill. So at what point do we just leave the U.S.? I mean,
many have already left. Oh, I am deeply empathetic to your lived experience in Chesa.
I will also add that, unfortunately, Donald Trump is not the sole cause of the current elevated
militarization. He is merely one in a world of individuals who have committed themselves to
destruction, which is why when I come here and I talk about things like softness and abundance,
and this is the type of stuff that we're doing and we're talking about, but through humor,
let me just do a shameless plug real quick, at my show on Wednesday, August 12th. You can come through,
uh, get your tickets at the website. The link is right here. Um, because I will be doing Radical
Rhythms Experience last week. I mean, last month I forgot to press live and so it didn't go live.
My bad. It won't happen again, but you can watch it live. Uh, and if you are in New York or the tri-state
area, meet me in Harlem, 7.30 PM next Wednesday, August 12th at the Comedy in Harlem space on 147th and St.
Nicholas. Yes, empire is falling and this is why it is imperative that we engage our empathy, that we
engage our softness, that we engage our matriarchal thinking to build in place of what has been here.
That's what's up, Ace Judy. We, I, I'm trying to, with my Patreon, with this show, Radical Rhythms Experience,
I am trying to, um, create community spaces where we are really talking about the root problem
of where we are in this world, which is us. We are the root problem.
Um, and so in order for us to change this world that we're in, we must change us. It's the same.
Thank you, Jam God Living. So every day I am working to do that. Okay. Is the sound back? We back? We back? We back? We back? We back? Okay. Sorry. I had a phone call.
Um, so I'm about to drop a series of shirts called the Unlikable Capsule.
It's a bit tongue in cheek because the shirts themselves have messages on them that are very distinct and that really speak loudly about who you are as a person.
And unfortunately, when you are a person that stands on truth, when you are a person that is passionate, uh, when you are a person that don't take no shit, it makes you unlikable.
And in a world that protects pedophiles, that elevates liars, that justifies genocide, that, um, that like runs behind mean girls in, in, in a world that does all of those things, you are going to be unliked when you do those other ones.
So it's just what it is. We are in the upside down, Marquise, for real.
And, um, I think that those of us, like, I know that in my Patreon, we love being able to see each other and know that we're not alone in our unlikableness.
Right? Right? We know that. So, um, look out for that.
And, um, if you're just joining this live, I hope you'll go back and watch it from the top.
I, I feel like we, we talked about some really interesting things here that I think can be really useful in just bringing some, some much needed grace and, um, love to your life.
So, um, so again, I want to see you guys out here in Harlem on August 12th, uh, next Wednesday for the Radical Rhythms Experience.
Radical Rhythms Experience is a show where I combine comedy and, uh, sorry, where I combine comedy and, there it is.
The Radical Rhythms Experience is a show where I combine comedy and mindfulness and energy work to just give us a, a, a, a little recalibration.
Okay?
And within that, of course, there's music.
So, uh, I hope you all will get your tickets. The link is right there in red.
You can also just go to, um, comedyinharlem.com.
All right?
So, have a good day.
Stay lifted.
And, uh, when the ops is out, stay low and stay firing.